Let's look at some shocking data.  A person is thinking of taking out
a health insurance plan with a coverage of 10 lakh rupees
.  They are the same age and live in the same city
.  If you were going to take an
Elevate plan from IIC, you
could have taken this plan for just 9500.  If you were to take the same HDFC Airco
Optimum Secure, you would have to
pay around 16,800.  Same
plan, same job, same city, same
number.  But it would be like buying it
from HDFC for almost twice the price
.  So, is Edifc
Silenta overcharging everyone
or is ICICI hiding
some hidden conditions and
selling their policies at a lower premium? In fact, at this point, if
you want to take health insurance, you will most likely be
told that they are flagship products, meaning that if
you look at two policies that are very good brands, one is Elevate from ICICI and the
other is
Optimas Secure from SDFC.  Both of these
plans have good features
, but neither of them has a co-payment
class.  There is no such thing as a disease-wise sub-
limit.  Similarly, there
is no limit for both rooms.  This means that even though the
two plans look the same on paper
, their cost
structures
are completely different.  Why is there such a big difference?
Which plan is right for whom is determined
by six different parameters. Even if they look the same on the surface
, when compared according to six different
parameters
, we ultimately have a
clear understanding of which is right for us.
Which company has the best claims track record
?  Which one gives the most bonuses
?  Which restaurant is better
?  In this video, we'll look at everything in detail, from the waiting period, actual
premium cost, flexibility, and even the fine print that
agents may hide without telling us.
Hello, my name is Busan. This
channel is Finance Busan.
Before you go to the video, this video is sponsored
by Ditto Insurance.
Ditto is the top-rated insurance advisor in India.   If you're
thinking of taking out insurance, the entire process
can be handled for you by their team of experts, free of charge.   If
you want to say Tito's value add is that
they are completely spam-free.  This means that if
you are thinking of taking out insurance, in most
cases
they will not send you any spam calls or emails that you do not need.  You can
also book an appointment with their experts at a time that is convenient for you
.  You can do all of this for free by calling at that time and
answering any questions you may have,
from the documentation process to addressing any questions you may have
before purchasing an insurance policy
.  I'll leave the link for doing this in
the description below or in the comments
.  Please check it out.  It's not
just about buying an insurance policy
.  They
will also help with the claim settlement process.   If you are
thinking about getting insurance for yourself or your family,
I highly recommend Ditto.
Definitely check out their website.
Now let's move on to the straight comparison
.  First, let's look at Round One, i.e., the
claims track record of these two companies
.   If we
are going to take out insurance,
this is the most important parameter to consider.  I mean, if we
go to make our insurance claim, will they
settle it?
This
track record will help you figure out if they are rejecting you.
Now, if we take the track record from 2021 to 2024,
that is, if we calculate the average, the
settlement ratio of IIC Lambda will be 85.24%
.  This means that if 100 claims are received,
they have settled approximately 85 of them
.  If you take the same HDFC,
they will have settled 96.7%.  HDFC Ecos has settled almost 97
claims, that is, 97 out of 100 potential claims
.  Almost 11% difference in the claim
settlement ratio. 11% is a
very significant value
.  This number is what determines whether we will be admitted to our hospital or
not
.  The higher this is, the
better the policy is.   There is only one
Edifco at the top of the list
.  This is easy, this
Beyond this claim settlement ratio, there will be an incurred claim
ratio.  In other words,
this ratio is what percentage of the total premium amount they can collect is spent on claims
.  According to this ratio, ICAI Lambda is
83% and HDFC is around 82%
.  It's almost on the same level
.  Both are healthy numbers
.  Next to this is customer
complaints, another very important
number.
This number
tells you how many complaints have been received out of a possible 10,000 claims.  This is in the range of
about nine for both companies.
This is the lowest number in the industry.
Because the overall industry average is
above 22.  The next
important thing is network
hospitals.  That means that even when you
say network hospital, it
supports cashless claims.  If we are admitted to our hospital for a while,
we don't
need to pay anything.
Insurance will cover the entire direct cost
.  If you and I are
admitted to a network hospital, we will first make our own arrangements
.  Otherwise, it would be like filing a
claim with the insurance company for reimbursement
.  The more network
hospitals there are, the
more hospitals we will be able to
get cashless claims.   In
this case, there are almost
13,000 network
hospitals in the SDFC network.
If we take the same ICIC Lambard, it will be 1020.  There are
almost 25 times
more network hospitals in this area
.  So what does that mean?   This
means that there are many SDFC Argola network hospitals, whether in small rural areas, towns, or even in big cities.  So, if the path is
clear after round one, SDFC can
be said to be the winner.  Even then, it can
be said that it took a very large lead in the Specific Claim Settlement Ratio and won by a large margin, surpassing IC.  Next, let's understand the
bonuses and restoration structure available for these two plans
.  That is, the coverage we can afford
.  If we take only 10 lakhs now,
will we only get 10 lakhs?  Is there
anything more additional than that?  If it's like that,
how long will
this bonus and
restoration last?  Now,
if we take Optima Secure with HDFC Bank, it will be a three-layer
act.  That means there is only one policy.   There
are three different layers to this.
Now, for example, if you
take out coverage for 10 lakhs, the first layer would
be called Secure Benefit.
That means if we
want to take out 10 lakhs of coverage on the first day, they will
give us another 10 lakhs as an additional payment.  So,
in total, we
have coverage for 2 million on the first day itself.
That means there are no conditions for this.
That means we don't need to wait
.  There are no
hidden conditions that say you shouldn't branch out
.
This secure benefit means we get double the coverage from the first day of purchase.
They are giving you something else, like a plus benefit, in the same plan.   This
means that every year when we renew our plan,
we get an extra 50% of the coverage.
That is, if we take it now for 10 lakh rupees, we
will expect it to come to 20 lakhs in the beginning.  Since our base
cover is 10 lakhs, they will add
another 5 lakhs
extra when we renew next year.  That means it's
like having a cover of 2.5 million from the second year.  If
we go to the next year, we will have a total coverage of 3 million
rupees.  This plus
benefit will be added until it reaches 100% of the coverage amount,
that is,
up to a maximum of 10 lakh rupees
.  So in this case, you will get a
plus benefit of up to 10 lakhs
.  You will already have a secured
benefit of Rs. 1 million
.  So
when we look at the third year, we will be paying the
same premium as if we had 3 million coverage
.  If I had to
say the best point about this is that many
insurance companies
will give us a refund or bonus like this.  But it will be a no-claim bonus
.  That means they'll only
give you an extra bonus if you didn't do any branching last year
.  There are no such conditions
here.  This is a
rare benefit in the industry.
After this,
they will also give restoration benefits.  That means if our base plan of
10 lakh rupees
was empty, they would have added another
10 lakh rupees as restoration benefit for the same year
.  So we can use that too
.  That's why
they call this polysiox benefit.  This 4xx benefit means that if we
take a policy of 10 lakhs,
we get cover of up to 40 lakhs after one point
.
Now, if we take the Elevate plan with IICI Lambda
, their bonus
structure and presentation will be a little
different.  They also
give us bonuses for renewing our contracts year after year.  That means, when
our policy expires one year, and the
next year starts, they give us a 20% bonus
.  If we have base coverage of 10 lakhs, it
will become 12 thousand next year.
It will turn 14 next year.
Every year,
our bonus increases as we renew.
But if I had to say, a big plus in this plan is that they
offer unlimited restoration.  This means that if
our base plan is completely empty within a year, they will
restore it again
.  If it
becomes empty again due to hospital bills, they
will restore it again.  Making this unlimited is
a special
feature in the industry.
I can say that IIC is unique in this.
Infact, they have a lot of people
.  We can base it on that and
get extra bonuses.  Now, for
example, they
have an add-on called Power Booster.  So what does it
mean? If we feel like we are lacking in 20% bonus every year, we
can get a 100% bonus through this power booster.  If we add the add-
ons we need when purchasing the policy, we
can increase our bonus accordingly.
But if you look at it overall, that is, if you look at what
gives us the most coverage on Day One, then
HDFC is the one that
gives us the most.  But if we use add-ons on IIC, it will
be like IIC, which gives us a lot of coverage in the first case.  So in this
comparison,
we can say that both are glucose-rich.  If you ask a person, they might say that if
you get double the coverage on the day itself, then the
ADFC Slitta has a slightly higher edge
.  If we were to
pick one,
we would say that STFC is the winner by a narrow margin.
Next is the waiting period.  This is
almost the same for both policies
.  That is, the first 30 days of taking out the policy
are called the initial waiting period.  This is 30 days for both policies
.
We will also call it the specific illness waiting time.  This means that there is a
two-year
waiting period for both types of illnesses, such as hernia and cataract.  Next to this is a
waiting period of two to three years for pre-existing diseases
.  But, this three-year pre-
existing waiting period is a very
important thing.  In many
families, parents have pre-
existing conditions, such as diabetes or hypertension.
They offer add-ons for both plans to skip this.  If you use the
Jump Start add-on when purchasing an IIC policy, the
three-year
waiting period will be reduced.
Even if you have asthma, diabetes, high blood pressure, high
cholesterol, or obesity, the
waiting
period for angioplasty will be reduced to 30 days.  If
we give the same STFC, ABCD, he
gives an add-on called chronic care.  That means the waiting period for asthma, blood
pressure, cholesterol, and diabetes
is reduced for all four.  They
will all be reduced by 30 days.  So, we can say that
both policies ended with the same score in this round
.  In the
next round, we will compare the actual premium
value.  That is,
let's understand how much of a policy is tied to a month or a year.  Now, let's
take an example: a 30-year-old person
living in a city like Chennai or Delhi.  If he wants to have a coverage of 10 lakhs
,
he
can get this coverage by spending ₹9,500 per year on an ICICI Lombard plan.   If
you were to buy the same HDFC Optima Secure, it would have cost you
around 16,800 per year
.  Now take a family
.  Assuming both people are 30
years old, the
IIC premium in that case would
be almost 14,000.  The premium for the same HDFC Yoda would have been
around 24,000
.  Are
you thinking of taking a family floater plan?   This
means that for a family of two adults and one child, the
premium for IIC will
be in the range of 18,600.  If we look at this same HDFC,
they will charge almost 29000.  So, if
you look at Cleara, IIC, HDFC, you can say that it is 50% to 70%
cheaper
.  But it's a
very important thing to keep in mind.  If
we take a Rs 10 lakh policy from HDFC,
they default to Rs 20 lakh from day one
.  So what our
competitors are doing is not 10 lakhs or 10 lakhs
.  We even compare 10 lakh to 20 lakh policies
.  So it is
somewhat reasonable for HDFC to be twice as large
.  So, if we compare this,
how much will we pay for one lakh coverage?
When you look at it that way, HDFC is a bit cheaper
.  But if you look at the premium alone,
IICI can
be said to be the winner in this round.  Next, let's
see which plan is better in terms of add-on flexibility.  That means
we have purchased a policy.
We need some flexibility for that.   If
you want customization, you
can add it on top of the other ones.  Looking at it this way,
there are almost 29 add-ons in ic's Elevate plan.  But SDFC Yoda
plan only has six add-ons
.  So, in terms of flexibility, I
can say that IIC is better.  If
you want to say that Infact has a few good add-ons,
they're saying something called Infinite Care.   This
means that if we turn on that add-on,
we will get unlimited coverage
.  If a certain disease
costs more than our basic coverage, we can only claim that much with
this add-on, which is a single claim with unlimited coverage
.
They are also offering cashless treatment worldwide.
Up to 3 crore rupees.  You seem to be
traveling a lot abroad these days
.  If you are in a situation where you need to get treatment there
, if you
have this addon, you
can claim cashless worldwide.  Pre-existing disease
reduces wait time.  Not only that, but you can also
get a lot of add-ons specifically for IIC, such as personal accident cover.  If we take the same HDFC, we will only give a very
limited set of add-ons
.  They also have
an add-on for Unlimited Restaurant
.  This is almost
like their Infinite cover.  This means that
we can get unlimited coverage
by adding this.  Similarly,
they also
have a separate add-on that reduces the waiting time for pre-existing diseases.  Not only that,
they have an option called Aggregate Detectable.  So what does that
mean? If
something
happens to you up to a specific amount per year, I'll put my money in.   On
top of that, I'd say he's got an insurance kick
.  Doing so will
reduce the premium.  But if
you ask me what a person is,
tell me it's better to avoid it.  Next up is the
fine print round, which is the most important round for making
the decision we can make complete
.  Now, if we go to buy our actual product,
I'll understand in detail what's going on in reality.
Now, if you go to buy an ICICI plan, it will be
like adding one or two more add-ons.  If we look at the general base cover
alone, it
won't cost ₹9500.  When you
place an order online, they will pick up the item at almost the same price as HDFC
.  Similarly, we may have seen
a feature called unlimited restoration on IIC
.  That feature
doesn't always work by default.
This only kicks in after you make a claim and exhaust your base coverage completely.  For
example,
you have taken out coverage of 1 million rupees for the first claim you can make in a year.   If the
first claim costs more than 10 lakhs,
unlimited coverage will not be available for this first claim.
Unlimited coverage will only be available for the next claim after it has been fully exhausted.  This
can't be called a secret.  But
many people don't understand this detail clearly
.  Even though HDFC Optima Secure's plan may seem
expensive
, they add
all the strong features we need right in that base plan
.  Similarly,
SDFC is at
the top because it has a track record that can be claimed, which is very important.  So, you could
say that both are top plans from top brands in India.  Actually,
both are good health insurance
policies.  If you want to make juice,
you have to be young and healthy, and
you have to have premium gum.
Similarly, you have to customize it for your situation
.  If you're
thinking about needing an advance,
ICICI's Elevate plan is a good
choice.  No, the most important thing is the
settlement for you and your family
.  That means if I
go to Klaimaku, I can settle down without any problems
.  Similarly, if you
think I need to get twice as much as the base cover I put in at the beginning, HDFC Optima
Secure would be better.  That said, if you are
planning to take a comprehensive plan with all the children in the family, this would
be a preferable option.  Similarly,
if you want free, spam-free, honest advice when buying insurance, there's a link to it below
.  Please check it out.   You can
book an appointment at a time convenient for you and
get a free consultation with their team
.  Please ask and clarify any questions you may have
.  If you found the information you've seen in this video so far
useful or new, please
like this video
.  If you haven't subscribed to this channel yet,
click the subscribe button and then
click the bell icon next to it and
select All. You will immediately receive
notifications of new videos uploaded to this channel
.  Thank you, people.